底比斯 繁华之都
Thebes, city of the living.
法老塞提一世的冠上宝石
Crown jewel of pharaoh seti the first.
法老的大祭司 亡灵的看守人
Home of imhotep,pharaoh's high priest
伊莫顿的家乡
Keeper of the dead.
法老的宠妾 禁脔
Birthplace of ancksunamun,pharaoh's mistress.
安苏娜的出生地
No other man was allowed to touch her.
两人为了爱情 宁愿牺牲一切
But for their love,they were willing to risk life itself.
你们在这里干什么?
谁碰过你?
伊莫顿?!
我的祭司!
法老的侍卫!
你快走!不要管我!
不!
只有你才能让我复活!
我不能丢下你!
滚开!
你一定不会死的!
我一定会救你!
我的身体已经另有所属!
为了让安苏娜复活
To resurrect ancksunamun,
伊莫顿率领手下闯入墓穴把尸体偷运出来
Imhotep and his priests broke into her crypt and stole her body.
他们风驰电掣 深入大漠
They raced deep into the desert,
进入哈姆纳塔 亡灵之城
Taking ancksunamun's corpse to hamunaptra, city of the dead,
历代法老的陵寝…
Ancient burial site for the sons of pharaohs...
哈姆纳塔 公元前1290年
及其财富的陪葬地点
And resting place for the wealth of egypt.
伊莫顿为了爱人不惜怒犯天条 深入城内
For his love,imhotep dared the gods' anger by going deep into the city...
把亡灵黑经从圣取了出来
Where he took the black book of the dead from its holy resting place.
安苏娜的魂魄已经下到地府
Anck-su-namun's soul had been sent to the dark underworld
她的五脏六腑被剜了出来分置于五个瓮内
Her vital organs removed and placed in five sacred canopic jars.
安苏娜的魂魄被招了回来
Anck-su-namun's soul had come back from the dead.
但是紧追在后的侍卫突然闯进来…
But pharaoh's bodyguards had followed imhotep and stopped him...
打断了招魂仪式
Before the ritual could be completed.
他的僧侣因罪被活生生制成木乃伊
Imhotep's priests were condemned to be mummifiied alive.
至于伊莫顿…
As for imhotep
他被判接受"虫噬"
He was condemned to endure the hom-dai
古代诅咒中最恶毒的一种
The worst of all ancient curses,
因为太过恐怖所以从未施行过
One so horrible it had never before been bestowed.
他的灵魂生生世世…
He was to remain sealed inside his sarcophagus...
被密封于石棺之内
The undead for all of eternity.
受到袄教僧侣看守
The magi would never allow him to be released,
一旦他被释放将化为祸害人间…
For he would arise a walking disease, a plague upon mankind,
拥有千年法力的妖孽
An unholy flesh eater with the strength of ages,
力量笼罩这片土地所向无敌
Power over the sands And the glory of invincibility.
木 乃 伊
哈姆纳塔 l923年
三千年来 地上兵戎不断
For 3,000 years men and armies fought over this land,
地下妖气暗涌
Never knowing what evil lay beneath it.
而三千年来…
And for 3,000 years...
我们是法老侍卫的后代 世代看守着此处
We, the magi, the descendants of pharaoh's sacred bodyguards,kept watch.
恭喜你升职了
You just got promoted.
预备
Prenez vos positions!
沉住气
Steady!
你不会临阵脱逃吧?
You're with me on this one, right?
你的勇气给了我力量
Oh. Your strength gives me strength.
沉住气
Steady!
等一下!等等我
Wait! Wait for me!
沉住气
Steady!
开火
Fire!
跑 班尼 快跑
Run, beni! Run!
进去!快进去
Get inside! Get inside!
喂 不可以关门
Hey!Don't you close that door!
不可以关门
Don't you close that door!
怪物没有被发现
那他怎么办?
- 杀了他? - 不
沙漠会收拾他的
埃及 开罗 三年后
古物博物馆
圣石
''Sacred stones.''
雕塑和美术
''Sculpture and aesthetics.''
苏格拉底赛斯第一册 第二册…
Socrates, seth, volume one, volume two...
第三册
And volume three.
还有…
And t…
突司摩西斯王朝怎么会在这里?
Tuthmosis? What are you doing here?
T…T在哪?
''T.'' ''t,'' ''t,'' ''t,'' ''t.''
找到了
''T.''
我要把你放回原位
I'm going to put you where you belong.
救命
Help. Ooh.
哇!
Whoa-a-aaah!
糟了
Oops.
什么…怎么…
What… howci…
怎么…
Hhow…
你看看
Oh, look at this!
我的天哪!
Sons of the pharaohs!
我宁可要蝗虫 白蚁 老鼠
Give me frogs! Flies! Locusts!
都不要你
Anything but you!
和你比起来其他的灾难只是小儿科
Compared to you,the other plagues were a joy!
真的很抱歉 是意外
I am so very sorry.it was an accident.
拉美西斯摧毁叙利亚那才是意外
My girl,when rameses destroyed syria, that was an accident.
你…算是灾难
You...are a catastrophe!
看看我的图书馆
Look at my library!
我干嘛要忍受你?
Why do i put up with you?
你要忍受我是因为…
W well, you put up with me because i can…
我会读 会写古埃及文
I can read and write ancient egyptian,
我还会解释僧侣用的象形文宇
And i can i can decipher hieroglyphics and hieratic,
还有 我是方圆千哩以内
And, well,i am the only person within a thousand miles...
唯一知道该如何正确编码编目录的人
Who knows how to properly code and catalog this library, that's why.
我忍受你是因为你父母生前大力赞助本馆
I put up with you because your father and mother were our finest patrons.
愿他们的灵魂安息
That's why! Allah rest their souls.
我不管你要怎么收拾 要收拾多久
Now, i don't care how you do it,i don't care how long it takes.
你给我收拾好就对了
Straighten up this meshiver!
有人吗?
Hello?
阿杜?
Abdul?
穆哈德?
Mohammed?
巴布?
Bob?
你不会尊重死者吗?
Have you no respect for the dead?
我当然会
Of course i do!
有时候我宁可加入他们
But sometimes i'd rather like to join them.
要加入就快 不要害我像你一样失业
Well, i wish you would do it before you ruin my career the way you've ruined yours.
给我出来
Now get out!
我亲爱的…小妹 我要让你…知道
My dear, sweet baby sister, I'll have you... Know...
我的事业目前正要起飞
That at this precise moment my career is on a high note.
起飞?强纳森 我没心情陪你疯
''High note.'' ha! Jonathan, please, i'm really not in the mood for you.
我刚把图书馆弄得一团槽
I've just made a bit of a mess in the library,
班桥学院又拒绝了我的申请
And the bembridge scholars have rejected my application form again.
说我在考古这行的经验不足
They say i don't have enough experience in the field.
你还有我啊!小妹
You'll always have me, old mum.
而且我有东西可以逗你开心
Besides,i have just the thing to cheer you up.
拜托 强纳森 又是那些不值钱的小东西
Oh, no,jonathan,not another worthless trinket.
如果你再弄来一件垃圾
If i have to take one more piece of junk to the curator to try and...
要我…帮你出手…
Sell for you
你从哪弄来的?
Where did you get this?
在底比斯买来的
On a dig down in thebes.
我这辈子什么都没找到
My whole life i've never found anything, evy.
告诉我 这次没看错
Please tell me i've found something.
强纳森
Jonathan.
怎样?
Yes?
我想你找到东西了
I think you've found something.
你看纪念碑上的花饰
You see the cartouche there.
是塞提一世的王室封印我很确定
It's the official royal seal of seti the first, i'm sure of it.
大概吧! 我有问题
Perhaps. Two questions.
谁是塞提一世?他有钱吗?
Who the hell was seti the first, and was he rich?
他是l9王朝的第二位法老
He was the second pharaoh of the 19th dynasty,
据说是历来最富有的
Said to be the wealthiest pharaoh of them all.
很好 这位老兄
Good. I like this fellow.
我喜欢他 我查过了
I like him very much. I've already dated the map.
地图有三千年的历史
It's almost 3,000 years old.
你看这边的古埃及文…
And if you look at the hieratic just here,
那就是哈姆纳塔
Well, it's hamunaptra.
老天 胡说八道
Dear god, don't be ridiculous.
我们是学者 不是寻宝的人
We're scholars, not treasure hunters.
哈姆纳塔是古代阿拉伯人
Hamunaptra's a myth told by ancient arab storytellers...
拿来哄希腊游客的神话
To amuse greek and roman tourists.
我听过那些 木乃伊保护该城的谣传
I know all the blather about the city being protected by the curse of a mummy,
但是我的研究让我相信
But my research has led me to believe...
那城市可能确实存在
That the city itself may have actually existed.
我们说的是那个哈姆纳特?
Are we talking about the hamunaptra?
对 亡灵之城
Yes. The city of the dead.
据说是早期法老的藏宝库
Where the earliest pharaohs were said to have hidden the wealth of egypt.
对 在一间庞大的地下室内
Yes, yes, in a big, underground treasure chamber.
- 拜托 - 大家都听过
- heh! - oh, come on. Everybody knows the story.
只要法老下令启动机关…
The entire necropolis was rigged to sink into the sand on pharaoh's command.
整座墓地就会带著宝藏 沉入沙中
The whole place would disappear beneath the sand dunes, taking the treasure with it.
美国人会认为 那是骗人的童话故事…
As the americans would say, it's all fairy tales and hokum…
我的天哪 着火了
Oh, my goodness! Look at that!
城市的位置被你烧掉了
You've burnt it! You've burned off the part with the lost city.
我觉得烧掉比较好
It's for the best, i'm sure.
许多人浪费了一生
Many men have wasted their lives...
盲目的追寻哈姆纳塔
In the foolish pursuit of hamunaptra.
没有人找到过
No one's ever found it.
大部分的人…一去不回
Most... Have never returned.
别站着 快进门来
Come, come! Step over the threshold.
欢迎光临开罗监狱 我的家
Welcome to cairo prison, my humble home.
你说你是在底比斯买到的
You told me that you got it on a dig down in thebes.
你听错了 你骗我
Well, i was mistaken. You lied.
我对谁都说谎 向来一视同仁
I lie to everybody. What makes you so special?
我是你妹妹 所以你更好骗
I am your sister. That just makes you more gullible.
你在酒店从醉鬼身上偷来的 是顺手牵羊
You stole it from a drunk at the local casbah. Picked his pocket, actually.
所以我不认为 别开玩笑了
So i don't think it's a very good-- stop being so ridiculous.
这家伙为什么坐牢? 这我就不清楚
What exactly is this man in prison for? This i do not know.
不过我听说你要来 已经问过他了
But when i heard that you were coming, i asked him that myself.
他怎么说?
And what did he say?
他说 他只是在找乐子
He said he was just looking for a good time.
就是从他身上偷来的? 没错
This is the man that you stole it from? Yes, exactly.
不如我们去吃午饭… 你是谁?
So why don't we just go sniff out a spot of tiffin who are you?
- 这婆娘是谁? - 婆娘?
- and who's the broad? - ''broad''?
我只是本地传教的人 来传福音的
I'm just a local sort of missionary chap, spreading the good word.
这是我妹妹 伊芙 你好
But this is my sister evy. How do you do?
- 她还不算太难看 - 你说什么?
- oh, well.guess she's not a total loss. - i beg your pardon.
失陪一下
I'll be back in a moment.
问他盒子的事
Ask him about the box.
我们找到了 喂 对不起
Um, we have found uh, hello. Excuse me.
我们找到你的魔术盒
We both found your puzzle box,
想请教你一些问题
And we've come to ask you about it.
- 不对 - 不对?
- no. - no.
不对 你是来问我哈姆纳塔在哪
No. You came to ask me about hamunaptra.
你怎么知道盒子和哈姆纳塔有关?
Shh. Shh. H-how do you know the box pertains to hamunaptra?
因为我就是在那里找到的
Because that's where i was when i found it. I was there.
我们怎么知道你不是在吹牛?
But how do we know that's not a load of pig's wallow?
我认识你吗?
Do i know you?
不认识 我有一张大众脸
No, no. I've just got one of those faces.
你真的去过哈姆纳塔?
You were actually at hamunaptra?
对 我去过
Yeah, i was there.
- 你发誓? - 每天发
- you swear? - every damn day.
我不是那意思 我知道 我去过那儿
I didn't mean that i know. I was there.
塞提的地盘 亡灵之城
Seti's place. City of the dead.
能告诉我怎么去吗
Could you tell me how to get there?
我是说 确实的位置
I mean, the exact location.
- 你想知道? - 想
- you want to know? - well, yes.
- 你真的想知道? - 对
- Do you really want to know? - Yes.
那就把我弄出去
Then get me the hell out of here!
快去
Do it, lady!
他们要带他去哪?
Where are they taking him?
绞刑台
To be hanged.
看样子他找到乐子了
Apparently he had a very good time.
我给你一百镑 你放了他
I will give you 100 pounds to save this man's life.
我给你一百镑看他被吊死
Madame, i would pay 100 pounds just to see him hang.
两百镑 行刑
Two hundred pounds! Proceed!
三百镑
Three hundred pounds!
有什么最后要求?死猪
Any last requests, pig?
有 把绳子松了 放我走
Yeah. Loosen the knot and let me go.
我们怎么可能放他走
Y ahemar! Of course we don't let him go!
五百镑
Five hundred pounds!
还有呢?
And what else?
我是个寂寞的男人
I'm a very lonely man.
- 行刑 - 不要
- Yalla tlak! - No!
哈!他的脖子没有断
Ha ha! His neck did not break!
很抱歉 现在我们得看他被勒死
Oh, i'm so sorry. Now we must watch him strangle to death.
他知道哈姆纳塔的位置
He knows the location to hamunaptra.
- 你骗人 - 我才没有
- You lie. - I would never!
你是说这只恶心的猪知道亡灵之城在哪?
Are you telling me this filthy, godless son of a pig knows where to find the city of the dead?
- 没错 - 真的?
- yes! - truly?
如果你放他下来我们就分你…
Yes! And if you cut him down, we will give you…
- 一成 - 五成
- Ten percent. - Fifty percent.
- 两成 - 四成
- Twenty. - Forty.
- 三成 - 两成半
- Thirty! - Twenty five.
好 成交
Ah! Deal.
放他下来
Ahh! Cut him down!
开罗 吉萨港
他真的会出现?
Do you really think he's going to show up?
当然会 我的运气这么好
Yes, undoubtedly, knowing my luck.
他是那种说话算话的人
He may be a cowboy, but i know the breed. His word is his word.
我觉得他下流 粗鲁 根本就是无赖
Well, personally i think he's filthy, rude, a complete scoundrel.
我不喜欢他 在等我吗?
I don't like him one bit. Anyone i know?
哦 你好
Um, hello.
适合冒险的好日子 对不对?欧康诺
Smashing day for the start of an adventure, eh, o'connell?
对啊!好日子
Yeah. Yeah, smashing.
大家是自己人 我不会打你的主意
Oh, no, no, i'd never steal from a partner... Partner.
说起来 不好意恩…
That reminds me. No hard feelings about the…
- 没关系 常有的事 欧康诺先生
- oh, no, no. Happens all the time.  Mr.O'connell.
你可不可以向我保证绝对不是在吹牛?
Can you look me in the eye and guarantee me this isn't some sort of a flimflam?
否则的话 我警告你… 你警告我?
Because if it is, i am warning you… you're warning me?
小姐 我告诉你 我的部队就是信以为真…
Lady, let me put it this way: my whole damn garrison believed in this so much...
才会横越利比亚到埃及找那城市
That without orders, they marched halfway across libya and into egypt to find that city.
我们到了以后 找到的
When we got there, all we found...
只是沙和血
Was sand and blood.
我帮你拿
Let me get your bags.
你说得对
Yes, yes, you're right.
下流 粗鲁 根本就是无赖 不讨人喜欢
Filthy, rude, a complete scoundrel. Nothing to like there at all.
各位早
Bright good morning to all.
天哪!你来干嘛?
Oh, no. What are you doing here?
我是来保护我的投资 多谢你的关心
I'm here to protect my investment, thank you very much.
伯恩斯 别玩眼镜了 切牌吧!
Quit playin' with your glasses and cut the deck, burns.
没有眼镜 我连牌都看不到
Without my glasses i can't see the deck to cut it, dave.
欧康诺 我们欠一个牌搭子
O'connell, sit down. We could use another player.
- 我只赌命 不赌钱 - 从不?
- i only gamble with my life, never my money. - never?
赌五百块我们比你先到哈姆纳塔
What if i was to bet you $500 we get to hamunaptra before you?
- 你们在找哈姆纳塔? - 说对了
- you're looking for hamunaptra? - damn straight we are.
谁说我们要去的? 他说的
And who says we are? He does.
怎么样啊?
Well, how 'bout it?
赌不赌?
Is it a bet?
- 赌就赌 - 你凭什么这么有把握?
- All right, you're on. - what makes you so confident, sir?
- 你们又凭什么? - 我们有去过的人带路
- what makes you? - we got us a man who's actually been there.
真巧 因为欧
Oh, what a coincidence, because o'connell
轮到谁? 轮到我吗?
Whose play is it? Is it is it my play? I thought
各位 就这么说定了 晚安 强纳森
Gentlemen, we got us a wager. Good evening,jonathan.
晚安
Good night.
对不起 我不是故意要吓你的
Sorry. Didn't mean to scare ya.
唯一会吓到我的 是你的礼貌
The only thing that scares me, mr. O'connell, are your manners.
还在气我吻你?
Still angry about that kiss, huh?
那哪能算得上吻
Well, if you call that a kiss.
我是不是搞错了?
Um, did i miss something?
我们…要去打仗吗?
Are we are we going into battle?
小姐 那个地方有问题
Lady, there's something out there.
沙地下面有东西
Something underneath that sand.
我希望能找到一件古代的文物
Yes, well, i'm hoping to find a certain artifact.
其实是一本书
A book, actually.
我哥哥认为那里有宝藏
My brother thinks there's treasure.
- 你认为有什么? - 简单的说 邪门
- what do you think's out there? -in a word? Evil.
贝多因人相信哈姆纳塔受到诅咒
The bedouin and the tuaregs believe that hamunaptra is cursed.
我才不相信那些老掉牙的故事
Oh, look, i don't believe in fairy tales and hokum, mr. O'connell,
但是我相信那里有一本著名的古书
But i do believe one of the most famous books in history is buried there.
太阳金经
The book of amun-ra.
包含了古埃及全部的秘密符咒
It contains within it all the secret incantations of the old kingdom.
这本书让我从小迷上了埃及
It's what first interested me in egypt when i was a child.
我来这里就是为了追求我的梦想
It's why i came here sort of a life's pursuit.
所以你不在意那本书是不是用黄金打造的
And the fact that they say it's made out of pure gold makes no never mind to you?
- 对吧? - 原来你都知道
- Right? - You know your history.
我关心我的宝藏
I know my treasure.
顺便问一下
Um... By the way...
你为什么吻我?
Why did you kiss me?
我都快死了 反正没事做
I was about to be hanged. It seemed like a good idea at the time.
怎么了?我说了什么?
What? What'd i say?
太意外了
Aaah! Aah! Surprise!
你还活着 谢天谢地
My good friend, you're alive!
我担心的不得了
I was so very, very worried.
这不是我的老朋友班尼吗?
Well, if it ain't my little buddy beni.
我要宰了你 想想我的小孩
I think i'll kill you. Think of my children.
你没有小孩
You don't have any children.
- 将来会有 - 闭嘴
- Someday i might. - Shut up!
原来美国人的领队是你 难怪
So you're the one who's leading the americans. I might have known.
你打算把他们骗进沙漠 然后丢下他们自生自灭?
So what's the scam? You take them into the desert, and then you leave 'em to rot?
可惜不行
Unfortunately, no.
这些美国人很聪明
These americans are smart.
他们先付一半 另一半回来给
They pay me only half now, half when i get them back to cairo.
所以我不能半路开溜 真倒霉 对不对?
So this time i must go all the way. Them's the breaks, huh?
你从来都不相信有哈姆纳特
You never believed in hamunaptra, o'connell.
为什么你要回去?
Why are you going back?
看到那位小姐吗?
You see that girl?
她救了我一命
She saved my neck.
你一向都是感情用事
You always did have more balls than brains.
对
Yeah.
再见 班尼
Good-bye, beni.
欧康诺
O'connell!
乔治班桥…
George bembridge...
在l86…
In eighteen sixty…
在l865年…
Hmm. ''1865 was…
在…
Was…
别想了 一个吻有什么大不了的
Oh, for heaven's sake, girl, it wasn't that good of a kiss, anyway.
地图在哪?
Where is the map?
在 在 那里
It's…it's... There.
钥匙呢?钥匙在哪?
And the key? Where is the key?
钥匙?什么钥匙?
The key? The key? What key?
- 伊芙琳
- evelyn!
地图!我忘了带地图
The map! The map! I forgot the map!
放心 我认得路 全都在我脑子里
Relax. I'm the map. It's all up here.
那我就放心了
Oh, that's comforting.
钥匙 伊芙?
The key! Evy?
拿着
Hold on to this.
你会游泳吗?
Can you swim?
如果有必要的话 当然会游
Of course i can swim, if the occasion calls for it. Trust me.
现在有必要 相信我
It calls for it.
欧康诺!欧康诺
O'connell! O'connell!
我们怎么办?
What are we going to do?
- 在这里等 我去求救 - 好
- Wait here! I'll go get help! - Right!
美国人
Americans.
我说 好枪法 老兄
I say, bloody good show, chaps!
我有惊惶失措吗?
And did i panic?
当然没有
I think not.
把马匹拉上来
Get out of here!
把它们拉上去!来啊!
Get 'em out of the water! Come on, dogies!
帮下忙 行不行
Give 'em a smack, would ya!
一塌糊涂的国家
This is a messed-up country.
我们什么都没了 所有的工具 设备
We've lost everything! All of our tools, all the equipment!
我全部的衣服
All my clothes!
欧康诺
O'connell!
喂 欧康诺
Hey! O'connell!
看样子 马匹都在我这边
It looks to me like i've got all the horses!
喂 班尼
Hey, beni!
看样子 你上错岸了
Looks to me like you're on the wrong side of the river!
干
Yeah.
我只要四匹 四匹
I only want four! Four!
我要的是四匹 不是一群
I only want four, not a whole bloody herd!
天哪!你能相信吗
O'connell! Ohh! Can you believe the cheek?
你付钱行不行
Just pay the man.
老天爷
Oh, for heaven's sake.
几匹臭骆驼还要这么贵
Can't believe the price of these fleabags.
开心啦!非常好
Yes, happy. Very good.
你只要把你妹给他
You probably could've got 'em for free.
就不用付钱了 对啊!
All you had to do was give him your sister. Yes.
是不是很吸引人?
Awfully tempting, wasn't it?
是
Awfully.
我不喜欢骆驼
Never did like camels.
他们又脏
Filthy buggers.
又臭还会咬人 流口水
They smell, they bite, they spit.
讨厌死了
Disgusting.
我认为它们很可爱
I think they're adorable.
这家伙很强壮
早安 朋友
Good morning, my friend.
我们在这边干嘛?
What the hell we doin'?
耐心点 我的朋友
Patience, my good barat'm. Patience.
记得我们打的赌吗? 谁先进城谁赢五百块
Remember our bet, o'connell. First one to the city, 500 cash bucks.
你帮我们赢了就给你一百块
A hundred of them bucks is yours if you help us win that bet.
乐意效劳
Oh, my pleasure.
嘿 欧康诺
Hey, o'connell.
骆驼不错嘛!
Nice camel.
准备了
Get ready for it.
准备什么?
For what?
目的地就快要出现了
We're about to be shown the way.
你们快看
Will ya look at that.
你能相信吗?
Can you believe it?
哈姆纳塔
Hamunaptra.
我们又来了
Here we go again.
再见 班尼
So long, beni!
- 你活该
- that serves you right.
Teek-teek-teek-teek! Hut-hut-hut!
Teek-teek-teek!
Teek-teek-teek-teek!
加油 伊芙 加油
Whoo-hoo! Go, evy! Go!
他们是不是有事瞒著我们?
Do they know somethin' we don't?
他们听女人的指挥
They are led by a woman.
女人懂什么?
What does a woman know?
这是死神像
That's a statue of anubis.
死神的腿深入地下
Its legs go deep underground.
据考古学家说神像腿部有秘密隔间
According to bembridge scholars, that's where we'll find a secret compartment...
收藏着太阳金经
Containing the golden book of amun-ra.
强纳森 你一是要对着阳光
Jonathan, you're meant to catch the sun with that.
这些旧镜子有什么用?
So, uh, what are these old mirrors for?
是古镜 古埃及的把戏等一下你就知道了
Ancient mirrors. It's an ancient egyptian trick. You'll see.
拿着 是给你的
Uh, here, this for, uh, you.
打开看 是我向我的美国朋友借的
Go ahead. It's something i borrowed off our american brethren.
我想你可能会喜欢
I thought you might like it
你应该用得到 就是
You might need it for when you're, uh uh, yeah.
看什么看?
What are you lookin' at?
看看有没有虫
Hey! Look for bugs.
我最讨厌虫
I hate bugs.
你能想像我们是三千年来的第一批访客
We're standing inside a room no one has entered in over 3,000 years.
什么味道这么臭?
Whoo! What is that god awful stench?
然后光线…
And then there was...
折射进来
Light.
嘿 很特别的把戏
Hey, that is a neat trick.
天哪 是防腐间
Oh, my god. It's a sah-netjer. Huh?
一间准备室 准备什么?
A preparation room. Preparation for what?
准备进入来世
For entering the afterlife.
这是他们制作木乃伊的地方
Mummies, my good son. This is where they made the mummies.
什么声音?
What was that?
那是什么?
听起来像…虫
Sounds like... Bugs.
他说是虫
He said bugs.
什么虫?我最讨厌虫了
What do you mean, bugs? I hate bugs.
死神的腿
The legs of anubis.
秘密隔间应该就在底部的某个地方
The secret compartment should be hidden somewhere inside here.
差点被你们吓死
You scared the bejesus out of us, o'connell.
彼此彼此
Likewise.
- 那是我的工具 - 我不认为
- hey, that's my tool kit. - i don't think so.
算…了
Okay.
大概是我看错了
Perhaps i was mistaken.
失陪了 各位 我们还有很多工作要做
Have a nice day, gentlemen. We have a lot of work to be getting along with.
- 滚开 这是我们的地盘 - 是我们先到的
- push off. This is our dig site. - we got here first.
老兄 这是我们的雕像
This here's our statue, friend.
怎么上面没刻你的名字?
I don't see your name written on it... Pal.
但是 你们只有四个人…
Yes, well, there's only four of you...
我们有十五个
and 15 of me.
你的胜算不大 欧康诺
Your odds are not so great, o'connell.
少来唬我 我也是
I've had worse. Yeah, me too.
听我说 小朋友 大家不要吵了
Oh, look, for goodness' sake, let's be nice, children.
如果大家要一起玩 就要学会分享
If we're going to play together, we must learn to share.
还有别的地方可以挖
There are other places to dig.
根据这些象形文字
According to these hieroglyphics,
我们是在雕像下面
We're underneath the statue.
应该从他双腿之间挖上去
We should come up right between his legs.
等那些死老美睡了以后 别介意 无所谓
When those damn yanks go to sleep no offense none taken.
我们再往上挖 偷走那本书
We'll dig our way up and steal that book right out from under them.
你确定我们找得到?
Are you sure we can find this secret compartment?
只要没有被那些死美国人先找到
Oh, yes, if those beastly americans haven't beaten us to it.
- 别介意 - 无所谓
- No offense. - None taken.
我们的小胖子去哪了?
Where'd our smelly little friend get to?
看
Hey.
我们找到什么了
What have we here?
蓝色的金子
Blue gold.
可以卖到一大笔钱
This will fetch a mighty fine price.
我们动手吧! 小心
Let's get us some treasure! Careful!
法老塞提不是笨蛋
Seti was no fool.
我觉得应该…让工人来橇开它
I think perhaps we should let the diggers open it, hmm?
博士说的很有道理 韩德森
Oh, i think we should listen to the good doctor, henderson.
好啊就让他们来
Yeah, sure. Let them open it.
你是说他们把内脏扯出来装进瓮里
They ripped out your guts and stuffed them in jars.
还有你的心脏 你知道他们怎么拿脑子吗?
They'd take out your heart as well. You know how they took out your brains?
你不需要告诉我们
I don't think we need to know this.
把一枝烧得通红的火钳插进你的鼻孔…
They'd take a sharp, red-hot poker, stick it up your nose
把脑浆稍微搅烂 然后用力拉出来
Scramble things about a bit and then rip it all out through your nostrils.
一定很痛
That's gotta hurt.
别担心 那时候你已经死了
It's called mummification. You'll be dead when they do this.
先说好 我就算出不去都不当木乃伊
If i don't make it out of here, don't put me down for mummifiication.
我也不当
Likewise.
我的天 是…
Oh, my god. It's a…
是具石棺
It's a sarcophagus.
埋在死神的脚底下
Buried at the base of anubis.
他如果不是身世显赫
He must have been someone of great importance.
就是…犯了滔天大罪
Or he did something very naughty.
阿拉
Oh, allah.
再一个
One more.
救命!快救我…
Help me! Help me!
救我
Help me!
到底是谁?
Well, who is it?
他不配留下姓名
''He that shall not be named.''
看起来好像是锁
This looks like some sort of a lock.
不管是谁都别想出来 真的
Well, whoever's in here sure wasn't getting out. Yeah, no kidding.
没有钥匙 要一个月才撬得开
It'd take us a month to crack into this thing without a key.
钥匙?
A key?
钥匙 钥匙 原来那个人说的就是这个
A key! A key! That's what he was talking about!
谁? - 船上的铁钩人
- who? - the man on the barge.
他在找一条钥匙
The one with the hook. He was looking for a key.
喂 那是我的
Hey, that's mine.
你想他为什么会死? 因为暴饮暴食
What do you suppose killed him? Did you ever see him eat?
看来美国人今天的运气也不好
Seems that our american friends had a little misfortune of their own today.
有三名挖掘工人…溶化了
Three of their diggers were, uh... Melted.
什么?怎么溶化?
What? How?
盐酸 高压盐酸
Salt acid. Pressurized salt acid.
中了某种古老的陷阱
Some kind of ancient booby trap.
可能真的有诅咒
Maybe this place really is cursed.
拜托 你们两个
Oh, for goodness' sake, you two!
你不相信诅咒? 不信
You don't believe in curses? No, i don't.
我只相信碰得到看得到的东西
I believe if i can see it and i can touch it, it's real. That's what i believe.
我相信有备无患
I believe in being prepared.
看看我们的典狱长相信什么
Let's see what our friend the warden believed in.
- 什么? - 怎么了
- aaah! - my god, what is it?
一支破瓶子
A broken bottle.
十二年的威士忌酒
Glenlivet. Twelve years old!
他人不怎么样 品味倒不错
He may have been a stinky fellow, but he had good taste.
拿着 别乱跑
Take this. Stay here.
等一下 等等我… 伊芙
No, wait, wait! Wait for me. Wait! Evy!
他明明叫你不要乱跑
Excuse me, but didn't the man just say ''stay here''? Evy!
韩德森先生 快起来
Mr. Henderson! Wake up!
欧康诺
Hyah! O'connell!
够了 各位
Enough! Y allah!
我们不杀你们 但是你们必须走
We will shed no more blood, but you must leave.
不走就死
Leave this place or die.
你们有一天的时间
You have one day.
各位 我们走
Yallah! Nimshi!
伊芙琳
Evelyn.
小心
Hey.
你没事吧? 我没事
Are you all right? Yes, i'm fine.
- 你确定? - 谢谢
- You sure? - Thank you.
我就知道塞提的宝藏一定在地底下
That proves it. Old seti's fortune's got to be under this sand.
否则他们没有必要袭击我们
For them to protect it like this, you know there's treasure down there.
不 这些是沙漠民族 水对他们比黄金珍贵
No, these men are desert people. They value water, not gold.
你知道 或许在晚上我们可以合作
You know, maybe just at night, we could, uh, combine forces, hmm?
很厉害 试试看右钩拳
Hey, tough stuff, try a right hook.
把拳头提高 像这样
Ball up your fist and put it put it up like that.
然后用力 打这只手
Mm-hmm. And then mean it. Hit it right here.
我用力 好了
I mean it! Okay.
好了 我们休息一下
Okay, it's time for another drink.
先生 不像我哥…
Unlike my brother, sir,
我知道适可而止
I know when to say no.
小姐 你不像你哥
Uh-huh. And unlike your brother, miss,
我就是搞不懂你
You, i just don't get.
我知道 你一定奇怪…
Ah. I know. You're wondering...
像我这样的人怎么会来这种地方
What is a place like me doing in a girl like this.
差不多 这样
Yeah, something like that.
我天生喜欢埃及
Egypt is in my blood.
你知道…我父亲是…
You see, my my... father...
一位非常 非常有名的探险家
Was a very, very famous explorer,
他热爱埃及…
And he loved egypt so much,
所以娶了我母亲 她是埃及人…
He married my mother, who was an egyptian...
而且也是位探险家
And quite an adventurer herself.
我明白你的父母…
Hmm. I get your father, and i get your mother,
我也…
And, uh,
也明白他 但是…
I get him, but...
你来这里干嘛?
What are you doing here?
你听着 我或许不是…
Look,i may not be...
探险家
An explorer...
不是冒…险家
Or-or an adventurer...
不是寻宝家 更不是枪手
Or a treasure seeker or a gunfighter,
欧康诺先生
Mr. O'connell,
但是我以我的职业为荣
But i am proud of what i am.
那是什么?
And what is that?
我…
I...
是图书馆管理员
Am a librarian.
而且我要吻你…
And i am going to kiss you,
欧康诺先生
Mr. O'connell.
叫我瑞克
Call me rick.
瑞克
Oh, rick.
箱子上面有诅咒 诅咒个屁
There is a curse upon this chest. Curse, my ass.
谁会在意? 韩德森先生 你应该在意
Who cares? Have a care, mr. Henderson.
在这种地方 古代下的诅咒
In these hallowed grounds, that which was set forth in ancient times...
仍旧非常灵验 明白了
Is as strong today as it was then. We understand.
上面写什么?
What's it say?
凡开此箱者…
''Death will come on swift wings...
必难逃杀身之祸
To whomsoever opens this chest.
我们不该来的
We should not be here.
情况不太妙
This is not good.
上面还写着 此箱一开…
It says, there is one
原为圣律所封闭的怨灵…
The undead Who, if brought back to life, is bound by sacred law...
将破解诅咒 重返人间
To consummate this curse.
那我们就确定不要救活任何东西
Let's make sure we don't bring anyone back from the dead then.
他将杀尽所有开箱之人
''He will kill all who open this chest...
取其五脏六腑及血液
''And assimilate their organs and fluids,
藉此法而复生…
''And in so doing, he will regenerate...
由受诅咒之怨灵
And no longer be the undead.
化为祸害人间之妖孽
But a plague upon this earth.
我们大老远跑来 总算有收获
Well, we didn't come all this way for nothin'.
没错 是诅咒
That's right. It's the curse.
是诅咒
It's the curse.
是诅咒!小心诅咒!
It's the curse! Beware of the curse!
小心!
Beware!
迷信的死白痴
Stupid superstitious bastard.
我从小就梦想着这一刻
Oh, i've dreamt about this since i was a little girl.
你的梦想是死尸?
You dream about dead guys?
你们看 他的圣律被凿掉了
Look, his sacred spells have been chiseled off.
这个人不只这辈子而且下辈子都受到诅咒
This man must have been condemned not only in this life but in the next.
真不幸 是的 赚人热泪
Tough break. Yeah, i'm all tears.
现在…来看看里面是谁如何?
Now, let's see who's inside, shall we?
天啊我最讨厌他们这个样子
Oh, my god, i hate it when these things do that.
他的样子正常吗?
Is he supposed to look like that?
不对 我从来没看过这样的木乃伊
No, i've never seen a mummy look like this before.
他还是…还是…
He's still… still…
- 很新鲜 -对
- Juicy. - Yes.
他死了应该超过三千年了…
He must be more than 3,000 years old,
可是看起来好像还没有…
And, well, it looks as if he's still...
完全腐化
Decomposing.
你们看
Hey, look at that.
这你怎么解释?
What do you make of this?
天哪 这些痕迹是…
My god, these marks were made with...
指甲划的
Fingernails.
这个人是活着被关进去的
This man was buried alive.
他还留了一句话
And he left a message.
死亡只是开始
Death is only the beginning.
我的天!
Oh, my god.
它真的存在
It does exist.
这是亡灵黑经 一本书?
The book of the dead. A book?
管他什么书?宝藏在哪?
Who cares about a book? Where the hell's the treasure?
各位 这本书…
This, gentlemen,
是无价之宝
This is treasure.
少来了 你送给我我都不…
Hell, i wouldn't trade you for a brass…
你们看
Look at that.
那就是你们的宝藏
There's your treasure, gentlemen.
终于有点收获
Now we're onto something.
你要有钥匙才能打开那本书
I believe you need a key to open that book.
你想这些宝贝回去能卖多少钱?
Say, o'connell, what do you think these babies'll fetch back home?
听说你们找到新鲜的木乃伊
We hear you boys found yourselves a nice, gooey mummy.
恭喜
Congratulations.
把他晒干了 还可以当柴火卖
If you dry that fella out, you might be able to sell him for firewood.
看我找到什么
look what i found.
你坐了她的位子
You're in her seat.
- 起来 - 是
- Now! - Yup.
圣甲虫的骸骨 是种食肉虫
Scarab skeletons, flesh eaters.
我在他的棺材里找到的
I found them inside our friend's coffin.
这种虫有尸体吃 可以活好几年
They can stay alive for years feasting on the flesh of a corpse.
我们可怜的朋友被吃的时候还活着
Unfortunately for our friend, he was still alive when they started eating him.
所以有人丢这些虫进去让他慢慢被吃掉?
So somebody threw these in with our guy, and then they slowly ate him alive?
非常的慢
Very slowly.
他一定是不受欢迎才会被设计
He certainly wasn't a popular fellow when they planted him.
八成和法老的女儿走得太近
Well, he probably got a little too frisky with the pharaoh's daughter.
据我所知…
Well, according to my readings,
这种刑罚叫"虫噬" 是古埃及最恶毒的诅咒
Our friend suffered the hom-dai, the worst of all ancient egyptian curses
用来对付十恶不赦的罪人
One reserved only for the most evil of blasphemers.
我从来没听过这项诅咒被执行过
In my research, i've never heard of this curse having actually been performed.
那么厉害? 对 他们…
That bad, huh? Yes, well, they…
他们不执行是因为担心后果
They never used it because they feared it so.
书上说"虫噬"的罪人一旦复生…
It's written that if a victim of the hom-dai should ever arise
会带来埃及的十大灾难
He would bring with him the ten plagues of egypt.
你知道 这叫偷窃
That's called stealing, you know.
照你和我哥的说法…
According to you and my brother,
这叫借
It's called borrowing.
我还以为太阳金经是金的
I thought the book of amun-ra was made out of gold.
太阳金经的确是金的 这本不是太阳金经
It is made out of gold. This isn't the book of amun-ra.
这是另外一本
This is something else.
我想应该是亡灵黑经
I think this may be the book of the dead.
亡灵黑经?
The book of the dead?
那你还拿这本书来玩?
Are you sure you want to be playing around with this thing?
只是一本书 而且读书…
It's just a book. No harm ever came from...
不会有坏处
Reading a book.
这种事常发生
That happens a lot around here.
上面写什么?
So, what's it say?
太阳 太阴
""Amun ra. Amun dei. '"
意思是白天和夜晚
It speaks of the night and of the day.
不
No!
你不可以念出来
you must not read from the book!
快跑!
Run!
快 动作快
Go, go!
我们做了什么?
What have we done?
蝗虫是从哪来的?
Where the hell did they come from?
想知道就自己去查
I ain't waitin' around to find out.
我的眼镜 我的眼镜
My glasses. My glasses!
走开 走开
Leave me! Leave me!
喂!
Hey! Hey!
拜托你帮我找我的…
Could you help me find my gl… oh.
等等我!
Wait for me!
是谁?
Who's there?
谁在那里?
- 韩德森?
- henderson?
哥
Ah,jon!
圣甲虫
Scarabs!
- 伊芙 快跑 - 快走 快走
- Run, evy! - Go, go, go! Run!
- 伊芙琳? - 伊芙?
- Evelyn? - Evy?
伊芙?
Evelyn! Evy!
伯恩斯先生 谢天谢地
Oh. Oh, mr. Burns. Thank goodness.
我正在开始害怕
I was just starting to get scared.
我找不到他们…
I've lost everyone.
我的眼睛 我的眼睛
My eyes. My eyes.
救救我
Please help me.
我的舌头 他咬掉我的舌头
My tongue. He took my tongue.
- 拜托 不要丢下我
- please don't leave me.
安苏娜?
anck-su-namun?
该死!是扇活门
Damn it! It's a trap door.
开关一定就在附近
There's gotta be a switch or something around here someplace.
逃啊王八蛋 还不逃
Run, you sons of bitches! Run!
走
Go.
走 快走
Go! Go!
来吧 我的安苏娜
找到你了 玩什么捉迷藏
There you are! Will you quit playing hide-and-seek?
我们快走!
Come on. Let's get out of here. Whoa!
伊芙
Evy!
- 快走 - 当然 看到没有
- Move! - Yeah, right. Did you see that?
是活的 是活的
It was walking. It was walking!
我说过你们不走就死 你们不听
I told you to leave or die. You refused.
现在大家都得死
Now you may have killed us all,
你们释放了一头三千年的怪物
For you have unleashed a creature we have feared for more than 3,000 years.
- 放心 我杀了他 - 人类的武器杀不死他的
- relax. I got him. - no mortal weapon can kill this creature.
他不属于这个世界
He's not of this world.
- 混蛋 - 你们把他怎么了?
- You bastard. - What did you do to him?
我们从怪物手中把他救了回来
We saved him, saved him before the creature could finish his work.
你们要是不想死就马上离开
Leave, all of you, quickly, before he finishes you all.
各位 我们走
Y allah. Nimishi.
我们必须进去 想办法解决他
I must now go on the hunt and try and find a way to kill him.
我说过 他被我杀了
I already told you i got him.
记住
Know this.
这个怪物是死亡的使者
This creature is the bringer of death.
他不会饿 他不会累
He will never eat, he will never sleep...
他更不会停
And he will never stop.
愿上帝保护我
May the good lord protect and watch over me...
像牧者保护羊群一样
As a shepherd watches over his flock.
不行?
No? Okay.
奴隶的语言
我可能用得到你
你侍奉我…
大大有赏
请殿下吩咐
My prince.
其他的圣瓮在哪?
Teek-teek-teek-teek. Hut-hut-hut!
开罗 拜顿堡
你不是不相信老掉牙的故事吗?
I thought you said you didn't believe in that fairy tales and hokum stuff. Shoo!
遇到了会走路 会说话的三千年木乃伊
H- having an encounter with a 3,000-year-old walking, talking corpse...
让我不得不信
Does tend to convert one.
别想 立刻收拾 我们退房走人
Forget it. We're out the door, down the hall and we're gone.
不 我们不走 是 我们走
Oh, no, we are not. Oh, yes, we are.
不走 我们有责任阻止他
Oh, no, we are not. We woke him up, and we are going to stop him.
什么我们?我又没看那本书
''We''? What we? We didn't read that book.
我有没有叫你不要碰那本书?
I told you not to play around with that thing. Didn't i tell you?
对 是我 是我 所以我有责任阻止他
Yes, then me, me, me, me, i, i, i woke him up and i intend to stop him.
怎么阻止?那家伙说了寻常武器杀不死他
Yeah? How? You heard the man-- no mortal weapons can kill this guy.
那我们就要找不寻常的武器
Then we are just going to have to find some immortal ones.
又是我们 听我说好吗?我们不能…
There goes that ''we'' again. Will you listen to me? We have to do…
这个怪物一旦复生…
Aaah! Once this creature has been reborn,
他的诅咒会祸害人间
His curse is going to spread until the whole of the earth is destroyed.
那关我什么事? 这关所有人的事
Yeah? Is that my problem? It is everybody's problem.
伊芙琳 你救了我 我很感激
Evelyn, i appreciate you saving my life and all, but when i signed on,
可是当初我只答应带你过去和带你回来
I agreed to take you out there and to bring you back.
我已经交了差 履行了合约 没什么好说的
I have done that. End of job. End of story.
我对你而言就只是一张合约?
Contract terminated. That's all i am to you? A contract?
你要么就跟我走…
You can either tag along with me...
要么就自己留下来拯救全世界
Or you can stay here... And try and save the world!
- 怎样? - 我留下来
- What's it gonna be? - I'm staying.
随你 很好
Fine! Fine.
- 很好 - 随你
- fine. - fine.
- 随你
- fine. - ooh!
你知道 我是驻扎在本地的最后一名皇家空军
I'm the last of the royal air corps still stationed out here, you know.
哪个白痴的酒洒了
Some bloody idiot spilled his drink.
我的袍泽都战死空中长埋沙下
All the other laddies died in the sky and were buried in the sand.
他们个个都是好汉
Good chaps, every one of them too. Ooh.
嗨 温斯顿 欧康诺 你知道
Hi, winston. Ye... uh... you know, o'connell.
自从大战结束以后…
Ever since the end of the great war,
我就变成…英雄无用武之地
There hasn't been a single challenge...
是吗?我们都有烦恼
Worthy of a man like me. Yeah?
可恨我不能像其他战友一样…
We all got our little problems today, winston.
我只是希望我能够打发与他人
I just wish i could have chucked it in with the others...
轰轰烈烈的光荣殉职
And gone down in flame and glory,
只能无聊的坐在这边喝闷酒
Instead of sitting around here,Rotting of boredom and booze.
干杯!
Cheers. Mmm.
该回机场了
Mmm. Oh, well, back to the airfield.
- 你妹妹一向这么… 一向
Tell me, has your sister always been oh, yes, always.
那艘该死的船明天才能出发
We're all packed up, but the damn boat doesn't leave till tomorrow morning.
准备挟着尾巴逃了
Tail set firmly between your legs, i see.
你说得轻松 被追杀的又不是你
You can talk. You don't have some sacred walkin' corpse after ya.
你朋友还好吧?
So, uh, how's your friend?
眼睛和舌头都被人挖掉 你说会好吗?
He had his eyes and his tongue ripped out. How would you be?
非常高兴…
I'm so pleased...
见到你
To meet you.
伊莫顿殿下不喜欢人家碰他
Prince imhotep does not like to be touched.
那是东方的忌讳迷信
A silly eastern superstition, i'm afraid.
请不要见怪
Please forgive me.
糟糕
Oh-ho. Ohh. Whoops.
伯恩斯先生
Mr. Burns,
殿下谢谢你的热情招待
Prince imhotep thanks you for your hospitality.
不
No.
还要谢谢你奉献眼睛…
And for your eyes...
还有舌头
And for your tongue. Wha
不过 你必须继续奉献 什么?
But i am afraid more is needed. What？
殿下必须继续仪式…
The prince must finish the job...
完成诅咒你和你的朋友们 不!不!
And consummate the curse which you and your friends... No! No!
- 这是你们自己招来的报应 - 不…
- have brought down upon yourselves. - wait! No!
祝你们好运
Good luck, boys.
搞什么?味道像…
Sweetjesus! Tasted just like…
血
Blood.
埃及的江河一片殷红…
''And the rivers and waters of egypt ran red...
如鲜血一般
And were as blood.''
他找上门来了
He's here.
看样子会有暴风雨
Oh, looks like there's gonna be a storm.
- 伊芙琳 - 原来你还没走
- oh, evelyn! - oh, so you're still here.
我们有麻烦了
We've got problems.
喂
Hey!
你这个人渣 你躲哪去了
Beni, you little stinkweed. Where you been?
我们麻烦大了
We are in serious trouble.
是你释放了我
我谢谢你
我们真的麻烦大了
We are in very serious trouble.
他好像喜欢伊芙
He does seem to like evy.
你是什么意思?
Yeah, what's that about?
他到底想干嘛? 只有一个人能回答我们的问题
What's this guy want? There's only one person that can give us any answers.
- 你 - 卡纳汉小姐
- you! - miss carnahan.
- 男士们 - 他在这里干嘛?
- gentlemen. - what is he doing here?
你真的想知道还是想一枪打死我们
Do you really want to know, or would you prefer to just shoot us?
经过了刚才的事…
After what i just saw,
我愿意对你有点信心
I'm willing to go on a little faith here.
我们属于一个古老的秘密组织
We are part of an ancient secret society.
三千年来我们看守着亡灵之城
For over 3,000 years we have guarded the city of the dead.
我们立过誓会竭尽所能… 阻止大祭司伊莫顿重返人问
We are sworn at manhood to do any and all in our part to stop the high priest imhotep...
因为你们 我们失败了
From being reborn into this world. Because of you,we have failed.
你们这样就有藉口滥杀无辜?
You think this justifies the killing of innocent people?
为了阻止这个怪物?让我想想 对
To stop this creature? Let me think. Yes! Yes!
问题 他为什么怕猫?
Question: why doesn't he like cats?
猫是地府的守护者 也是他完全复生之前的克星
Cats are the guardians of the underworld. He will fear them until he is fully regenerated.
- 之后就什么都不怕了 - 你知道他怎么复生吗?
- then he will fear nothing. - you know how he gets hisself fully regenerated?
就是杀死所有开箱的人 而且吸干他们的血
By killin' everyone who opened that chest. And suckin' 'em dry!
强纳森 别再玩了
Jonathan, will you stop playing with that?
在哈姆纳塔看到他的时候 他叫我安苏娜
When i saw him alive at hamunaptra, he called me anck-su-namun.
刚才在旅馆的时候他还想亲我
And then just now in mr. Burns' quarters, h-he tried to kiss me.
他被诅咒就是因为爱上安苏娜
It's because of his love for anck-su-namun that he was cursed.
显然经过了三千年… 他还是爱着她
Apparently,even after 3,000 years… he is still in love with her.
很浪漫 但是关我什么事?
Yes, that is very romantic, but what has it got to do with me?
他会试着再次为她招魂
Perhaps he will once again try to raise her from the dead.
看来他已经选中了他的祭品
And it appears he has already chosen his human sacrifice.
你真倒霉
Bad luck, old mum.
相反的… 这正好给我们足够的时间
On the contrary, it mayjust give us the time we need...
来消灭他
To kill the creature.
我们需要所有的帮助 他的力量在增强
We will need all the help we can get. His powers are growing.
他向天伸出他的手…
And he stretched forth his hand towards the heavens…
埃及便笼罩在漆黑之中
And there was darkness throughout the land of egypt.
我们一定要阻止他
We must stop him from regenerating.
打开箱子的有谁? 有我和丹尼…
Who opened that chest? There was me and daniels here.
当然有伯恩斯 还有那个埃及学家
And burns, of course. And that egyptologist fellow.
- 那我朋友班尼呢? - 没有 我们打开之前他就溜了
- what about my buddy beni? - no, he scrammed outta there before we opened the thing.
- 对 他比较聪明 - 没错 他的一贯作风
- yeah, he was the smart one. - well, that sounds like beni.
我们要尽快找到埃及学家
We must find the egyptologist and bring him back to the safety of the fort...
在怪物找到他之前带他回来 好
Before the creature can get to him. Right.
她留下来 你们三个跟我走
She stays here. You three, come with me.
我要去 你凭什么不让我去
You can't leave me behind like some old carpetbag.
我干嘛要听你的?你以为你在干嘛?
Who put you in charge? O'connell, what do you think you are doing?
强纳森!欧康诺 对不起 他块头比我…大
Jonathan! O'connell! Sorry, but he's a bit... Tall.
欧康诺 你这个孬种你不能把我留在这里
Coward that you are! O'connell, you are not leaving me in here!
强纳森你要是不马上把门打开…
Jonathan, if you don't open this door in one minute flat…
不准开门 不准任何人进出 知不知道?
O'connell, let me out ofhere. This door doesn't open.
知道
She doesn't come out, and no one goes in, right? Right.
- 知道? - 知道
- right? - right.
欧康诺!强纳森 强纳森 我们走
O'connell! Jonathan! Let's go,jonathan.
我想我可以留下来…监视
Oh, i thought i could just stay at the fort and, uh, reconnoiter.
马上 对 我们只是要去救埃及学家
Now! Yeah, right. We're just gonna rescue the egyptologist.
来看看 让我猜 春季大扫除
Well, well, well. Let me guess. Spring cleaning.
丢得好
Nice shot.
班尼 跌倒啦 让我来扶你
Oh, beni, did you fall down? Let me help you up.
你在沙漠认识了一位新朋友对不对?
You came back from the desert with a new friend, didn't you, beni?
什么朋友?你是我唯一的朋友
What friend? You are my only friend.
你干嘛和他混在一起 对你有什么好处?
What the hell are you doing with this creep? What's in it for you?
帮他做事总比跟他作对好
It is better to be the right hand of the devil than in his path.
只要我服侍他 我就不会有事
As long as i serve him, i am immune.
不会有什么事?
Immune from what? Piszkas allat.
(外语)
什么意思? 我不要告诉你 你只会欺负我
What did you say? I don't wanna tell you. You'll just hurt me some more.
你在找什么?最好不要骗我
What are you looking for? And try not to lie to me.
那本书 在哈姆纳塔找到的那本书 他要拿回去
The book! The black book they found at hamunaptra. He wants it back.
他说那本书比黄金还珍贵
He said to me it would be worth its weight in gold.
- 他要那本书干嘛? - 我真的不知道
- what does he want the book for? - i don't know.
和救活他的死女朋友有关
Something about bringing his dead girlfriend back to life.
就这样 他只要那本书 我发誓
But that's all.he just wants the book, i swear.
只有那本书 我发誓 还有你妹妹
Just the book, i swear. And your sister.
除了那些以外…
But other than that…
挂了两个 还剩两个
That's two down, two to go.
那他就会去找伊芙
Then he'll be coming after evy.
警戒布署完毕 报告 一切正常
Guards in place! Reporting all clear, sir!
管他去死
To hell with this.
我到楼下喝杯酒 你要什么吗?
I'm goin' downstairs,get me a drink. You want somethin'?
- 我要一杯威士忌加冰 - 好
- Yeah. Yeah, get me a glass of bourbon. - All right.
- 还要杯纯威士忌 - 好 知道
- A and a shot of bourbon. - Yeah, okay, okay.
还要配酒的饮料 反正你要波本就对了
And a bourbon chaser. I'll get your damn bourbon!
连门都不关
Don't worry about the door.
安苏娜
Anck-su-namun.
喂 丑八怪 不要碰她
Hey, get your ugly face off ofher!
- 看我拿的是什么
- look what i got.
你没事吧? 嗯 我不确定
You all right? Well, i'm not sure.
根据传说… 在哈姆纳塔找到的那本黑经
Well, according to legend, the black book the americans found at hamunaptra...
应该可以让死人复活
Is supposed to bring people back from the dead.
我以前一直都不愿意相信
Until now it was a notion i was unwilling to believe. Believe it, sister.
相信吧!那家伙不就复活了
That's what brought our buddy back to life.
我在想 如果黑经可以让死人复活…
I'm thinking that if the black book can bring dead people to life…
那金经就应该可以杀死他 没有人知道
Then maybe the gold book can kill him. That's the myth.
所以我们必须把金经找出来
Now we just have to find out where the gold book is hidden.
伊莫顿 伊莫顿
Imhotep. Imhotep.
伊莫顿…
Imhotep.
最后的大灾难是
Imhotep. Last but not least,
我最喜欢的疖子和烂疮
My favorite plague-- boils and sores.
他们变成他的奴隶了
They have become his slaves.
看样子世界末日已经开始
So it has begun, the beginning of the end.
现在还言之过早 我们走
Not quite yet, it hasn't. Come on.
伊莫顿 伊莫顿
Imhotep. Imhotep.
根据考古学家的研究…
According to bembridge scholars, the golden book of amunra...
死神雕像内藏的是太阳金经
Is located inside the statue of anubis.
- 我们找到的却是亡灵黑经 - 没错
- That's where we found the black book. - Exactly.
看来那些老学究一定搞错了
Looks like the old boys at bembridge were mistaken. They mixed the books up.
他们把两本书的埋藏地点搞混了
Mixed up where they were buried.
既然黑经是藏在死神像内
So if the black book is inside the statue of anubis,
那金经一定是藏在…
Then the golden book must be inside…
快啊伊芙 快点 耐心是美德
Come on, evy. Faster. Patience is a virtue.
现在可不是
Not right now it isn't.
我看我先去发车好了 我知道了
Uh, i think i'll go and get the car started.
金经是藏在哈姆纳特的太阳神像内
I've got it. The golden book of amun-ra is at hamunaptra inside the statue of horus.
你们这些笨老头子
Take that, bembridge scholars.
伊莫顿
Imhotep.
快走 快走…
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
老兄 千万别熄火 我们快走
Get this thing in gear, boy. Let's get outta here. Evy!
伊芙 快上车 伊莫顿…
Come on, evy. Hurry up. Imhotep!
你会有报应的 班尼 你听到没有
You're gonna get yours, beni! You hear me?
- 你会有报应的 - 我又不是第一次听到
- you're gonna get yours! - oh, like i've never heard that before!
坐稳了
Hang on!
欧康诺 欧康诺
Hey! O'connell! O'connell!
快走 快走
Okay! Go, go!
退后 退后
Back! Back!
伊莫顿…
Imhotep. Imhotep.
是那个怪物
It's the creature.
他已经完全复生了
He's fully regenerated.
Keetah mi pharos
Aja nilo isirian.
来吧 我的公主
"come with me, my princess.
从此 你将永远属于我
It is time to make you mine forever."
是永恒属于我 白痴
For all eternity,idiot.
Koontash dai na
Aja nilo.
跟我走…
"take my hand,
我就放了你的朋友
And i will spare your friends.''
天哪!
Oh, dear.
你有想到办法吗? 我正在想 正在想
Have you got any bright ideas? I'm thinkin', i'm thinkin'.
你最好赶快想 如果我被他变成木乃伊
You better think of something fast, because if he turns me into a mummy,
我第一个找你算帐
You're the first one i'm coming after.
- 不 - 别开枪
- no. - don't!
- 不 - 他必须带我到哈姆纳塔举行仪式
- no! - he has to take me to hamunaptra to perform the ritual.
她说得对 只有暂时忍气吞声
She is right. Live today, fight tomorrow.
我们会再见的
I'll be seeing you again.
伊芙琳
Evelyn!
嘿 那是我的 谢谢你
Hey, that's mine. Thank you.
把他们杀了
不 放开我
No! Let go of me!
放开我
Imhotep. Let go of me!
- 再见了 我的朋友 - 回来 你这个…
- good-bye, my friend. - come here, you little…
伊莫顿 伊莫顿
Imhotep. Imhotep.
- 下去 - 快点
- imhotep. - come on!
- 那我妹呢? - 我们会救她出来 过来
- What about my sister? - We're gonna get her back! Go!
- 换你
- you're next!
过来 把手给我
Come on! Give me your hand!
- 你先走 - 快点
- you go! - come on!
快走
Go!
吉萨港皇家空军基地
早 温斯顿 有事商量
Morning, winston. Uh, a word?
你的问题和皇家空军有关系吗?
What's your little problem got to do with his majesty's royal air corps?
没关系
Not a damn thing.
- 危险吗? - 你很可能会一去不回
- is it dangerous? - you probably won't live through it.
天啊你是说真的?
Byjove, do you really think so?
我们碰到的人都挂了 凭什么你例外?
Everybody else we've bumped into has died. Why not you?
是什么…是什么情况?
What's the, uh… what's the challenge then?
营救美女 杀死坏蛋拯救世界
Rescue the damsel in distress, kill the bad guy and save the world.
温斯顿 在此听侯差遣
Oh! Winston havelock at your service, sir.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
我这个样子看起来好吗?
Do i bloody look all right?
你怎么样?
How you doin'?
看到没?从来没看过这么大的
See that? I've never seen one so big.
从来没有? 没有
Never? No!
滚开 滚开
Get off of me! Get off.
我要换工作
I need a new job.
我的天
Oh, my god.
我们回来了
We're back.
欧康诺
O'connell.
糟糕了
Oh, my god.
温斯顿 踩油门
Hey, winston! Pedal faster!
坐稳了
Hang on, men!
住手 你会杀了他们
Stop it! You'll kill them!
那就是目的
That's the idea.
战友们 我来了
Here i come, laddies!
我喜欢你那招飞沙走石
I love the whole sand wall trick.
很厉害 混蛋
It was beautiful. Bastard.
对不起
Excuse me.
要是不麻烦的话帮帮忙行不行
Um, a little help would be useful,If it's not too much trouble!
好了 来了
Yeah, yeah. All right.
温斯顿…温斯顿
Winston! Hey, winston!
是流沙 快退后
Quicksand! Get back! It's quicksand.
继续走
Keep moving!
像你这种卑鄙小人始终都会得到报应的
Nasty little fellows such as yourself always get their comeuppance.
是吗?报应?
Really? They do?
对 迟早的问题
Oh, yes. Always.
先搬大块的石头
I'd take those bigger stones first.
先搬上面的 否则会整个塌下来
Take them from the top, otherwise the whole thing will cave in on us.
你们搬快一点
Come on. Put your backs into it.
对 没错 就是那样
Yes, well, you've got the idea. Chop, chop.
等等
I say!
两位 你们过来看看
Gents, you should come and have a look at this.
什么
What?
跑进我手臂了
It's in my arm! My arm!
天啊!
Whoa!
快想办法 抓住他
Do something! Hold it!
快想办法…不要用刀
Do something! Do something! Not that! Not that!
欧康诺
O'connell.
Shatay wapay ku ra eck!
班桥学院的研究从来没提过这个
Bembridge scholars never wrote about this.
放开我 放开
Get off me. Get off.
杀了他们…
叫醒其他人
哇…
wha…
- 你看到… -对
- Can you see… - yeah.
- 你相信… - 对
- Can you believe… - yeah.
- 我们可以… -不行
- Can we just… - no.
这些家伙是干嘛的? 僧侣
Who the hell are these guys? Priests.
伊莫顿的僧侣
Imhotep's priests.
- 那简单
- all right then.
找到了
There he is!
你好 太阳神老兄
Hello,horus, old boy.
该关门了
Time to close the door.
走
Let's go.
安苏娜
Anck-su-namun.
欧康诺 强纳森
O'connell! Jonathan!
- 可恶 这些家伙还真难缠 - 继续挖
- these guys just don't quit, do they? - keep digging.
太阳金经
Oh! The book of amun-ra.
杀了怪物 把女孩救出来
Save the girl. Kill the creature. Aaaah!
你还在等什么?快走 快走
What are you waiting for? Get out! Get out!
你还好吧?我们走
You all right? Let's go.
因为你的牺牲 安苏娜将复生
而我将所向无敌
太阳金经 我找到了 伊芙
The book of amun-ra! I found it, evy! I found it!
太阳金经
闭嘴 救我出去
Shut up and get me off here,Jonathan!
把书打开 那是我们唯一的希望
Open the book,jonathan. It's the only way to kill him.
打开金经 找到那道符咒
You have to open the book and find the inscription.
我打不开 好像锁住了
Well, i can't open it! It's locked or something.
- 我们需要钥匙 - 钥匙在他袍子里
- we need the key, evy! - it's inside his robes.
- 欧康诺 - 欧康诺
- haah! - o'connell!
木乃伊
Mummies. Aah!
小心 下面还有…欧康诺
Look out! There's one down… o'connell!
找到符咒了
Here's an inscription.
守陵…守陵侍卫听命
rasheem… rasheem oola rasheem oola kashka!
糟了
Oh, boy.
太好了
oh, yeah.
情况是越来越好
This just keeps getting better and better. Ohh.
- 强纳森 快想办法 - 我?
- do something,jonathan. - me?
- 你可以命令他们 - 你一定在开玩笑
- you can command them. - you have got to be joking.
笨蛋 把封面上的符咒念完
Finish the inscription on the cover, idiot.
你就可以控制他们 对 没错
Then you can control them. Oh. Right.
算了
Uh-uh.
强纳森 赶快
Hurry up,jonathan!
- 我看不懂这最后一个符号 - 看起来像什么?
- i can't figure out this last symbol. - what does it look like?
是一只…鸟…一只鹳
It's a, uh, a bird… a stork!
妖…孽
A ahmenophus!
哦 原来如此
Oh, yes, i see.
哦 铲除妖孽
Uh, hootash im ahmenophus.
消灭他!
我命令你们消灭他!
我命令你们消灭安苏娜!
Fa-kooshka anck-su-namun!
- 安苏娜
-Anck-su-namun!
把书交出来
-伊莫顿 -安苏娜
-Imhotep -Anck-su-namun!
你的死期到了
伊芙 我拿到了
Evy! I've got it.
-分散他的注意力 -啊...
- keep him busy. - aaah! Oof.
没问题
No problem.
赶快 伊芙 赶快
hurry, evy!
不要催我
Hurry! You're not helping.
现在轮到你了
找到了
Oh! I've got it.
尘归尘 土归土
Kadeesh mal. Kadeesh mal.
该走的 不当留
Pared oos. Pared oos.
你不是说这样就可以杀死他
I thought you said it was gonna kill him!
他没有法力了
He's mortal.
死亡…
''Death...
只是开始
Is only the beginning.''
该走了
Time to go. Ohh!
你把书掉了
You've lost the book!
- 我不敢相信… - 快走
- Jonathan, i can't believe… - come on!
- 我们可以… - 不行 强纳森
- Couldn't we just… no,jonathan!
欧康诺
O'connell!
- 欧康诺 等我 - 过来 赶快
- o'connell! Wait! - come on, come on.
等我 拜托
Wait! Please!
把手给我
Come on, come on! Beni!
再见了 班尼
Good-bye, beni.
走开 走开…
Go away. Shoosh ma! Shoosh ma!
走开 不要过来
Aah! Shoosh ma! Shoosh ma!
不要过来 走开…
Shoosh ma! Get away!
- 小心 小心
- look out, look out!
谢谢你 真是谢谢你
Oh! Thank you. Thank you very much.
我和我的族人衷心的感激你们
You've earned the respect and gratitude of me and my people.
这没什么
Yes, well,it was nothing.
愿真神保佑你们平安
May allah smile upon you always.
你也…一样
And... Yourself.
随时效劳
Yes, anytime.
保重了
Stayout of trouble.
他就这样…丢下我们不管
He's just... Leaving us here.
我想我们又再度…空手而归
Well, i guess we go home empty-handed... Again.
我倒不觉得
I wouldn't say that.
拜托
Oh, please!
你呢? 亲爱的 要不要亲一个
How 'bout you, darling? Would you like a little kissy-wissy?